okay let's continue on in our coverage
好吧，让我们 继续在我们的覆盖范围
of machine level programming ii and i
的机器语言的II和我
think a six part series as i mentioned
认为六个 部分组成 的系列正如我所说
yesterday machine level programming is
昨日机器语言是
sort of the core of this course that it
排序本课程的核心，它
gives you a set of tools and
为您提供了一套工具 和
understanding that take you well beyond
理解是 ， 把你远远超出
what years to the average
什么年平均
run-of-the-mill of programmer or
运行中的磨 程序员 或
software developer would would know
软件开发者都知道
about and it's very powerful in terms of
关于它来讲是非常强大的
your better understanding of the system
您更好地了解该系统的
what goes wrong of why why programs
哪里出了问题，为什么，为什么节目
crash what the meaning of those are and
死机什么的意思是和
so it's a fairly core part of the
所以它的一个非常核心的部分
material as you know the data web is due
材料如你所知的数据网络是由于
tonight and the next way about is called
今晚 约被称为下一个方式
the bomb lab and I believe that's coming
炸弹实验室，我相信这是未来
out tonight as well so the bomb lab will
今晚还有这样的炸弹实验室将
rely on your ability to understand
靠你 的理解 能力
machine level code so the these two
机器级代码，以便这两个
lectures will actually be enough to get
讲座实际上是足以让
you started on some of the earlier parts
你开始对一些 早期部分
of that lab you'll learn a lot more at
该实验室的你会学到更多 的
recitation on Monday either in person or
朗诵周一亲自或
if you're viewing the recorded version
如果你正在浏览的记录的版本
of that that will help you move along on
那这将帮助你一起 继续 前进
bomb web like all the labs in this
炸弹网页就像这一切的实验室
course at least the first two we give
当然，至少前两个我们给
you a fair amount of time for them but
您对他们有相当数量的时间，但
don't be fooled into thinking that means
不要因此就认为这意味着
you can just slack off or work on other
你可以懈怠 或其他工作
courses and then the last few moments
课程，那么最后几分钟
jump in and finish this grab the bomb
跳，并完成这个抢炸弹
lab once you get the hang of what you're
实验一旦你得到你在做什么窍门
doing it's pretty of you can just kind
这样做是相当的，你可以只是种
of crank along but there's a certain
沿曲轴，但有一定的
learning curve that will take you to
学习曲线 ，将带你到
even get started on it effectively so
甚至开始使用它有效地使
don't put it off
不要把它关闭
ah
啊
um oh is this
嗯哦，是这样的
so last time we introduced the very
所以上次 我们介绍了很
basic principles of machine level
机水平的基本原则
programming the idea of there being
编程有 存在 的想法
special states that you have access to
你有 机会获得特殊状态
the registers which people came after
之后人 来到寄存器
class nestor register is part of memory
类内斯特 寄存器的 存储 部
no are they part of the cache no through
没有他们是 缓存的 一部分 没有通过
special they're different they don't
特别他们是不同的 ，他们 不
exist to a sea level program when you're
存在 当 你是 一个海拔 程序
programming and see you don't have any
编程，看你没有任何
visibility into them and in general
洞察他们和一般
today what we're going to do then is go
今天我们将做的就是 去
beyond the sort of very basics and start
超越那种非常基础和启动
talking about the control how you
谈论如何控制你
control the flow of execution of
控制的执行流
instructions in a at the machine level
在机器级别的指令
and how you use those techniques to
以及如何使用这些技术来
implement basic constructs conditional
实现基本构造条件
statements loops and switch statements
声明循环和switch语句
and then next time we'll talk about
再下一次，我们将讨论
procedures which weren't a whole lecture
这不是一个整 场讲座程序
of its own so that x86 and several
自己的，这样x86和几个
machines of its generation have these
其代光机有这些
curious little of one bit flags that are
那 是 一个位标志好奇的小
called condition codes and they're the
所谓的条件代码和他们的
basis of how conditional operations work
如何条件操作的工作基础
so to a machine level programmer then we
这样一台机器级的程序员，那我们
talked last time that you have
谈到你有 最后一次
visibility of the set of registers and a
该组寄存器和一个的可见性
and the memory but you also have more
和记忆，但你也有更多的
things and this is only a partial list
事情，这只是部分清单
actually there's more and more stuff
实际上，有 越来越多的东西
that you can add to this picture but we
您可以添加到这个 画面，但我们
talked about in the 64-bit x86 64
在64位x86 64畅谈
there's now 16 registers 8 of which have
现在有16个寄存器8，其中有
names that are historic based on old x86
名基于旧的x86是历史
stuff and 68 of which were introduced
的东西， 其中68引入
and so they simply named name those are
所以就简单地命名为 名称那些
8 through our 15 and of these registers
8，通过我们的15和这些寄存器
for the most part the only one that's
在 大多数情况下只有 一个那
really special is RSP it's the stack
很特别的是RSP它的堆栈
pointer it tells you where and we'll
指针时，它会告诉你在哪里， 我们将
learn a lot more about stacks starting
学到了很多有关 堆栈开始
next time but it's sort of where the
接下来的时间，但它的排序， 其中
most the
大多数
the state is that manages the execution
状态是管理执行
of procedures and so you can't just use
的程序 ，所以你不能只 使用
that or set it in arbitrary ways but the
即或以任意 方式而设置
other ones you more or less come in with
其他的你或多或少与进来
qualifications for that statement
资格的发言
there's another register that they call
还有，他们称之为另一个寄存器
the our IP which has nothing to do with
在我们的IP具有 无关
death it means that the IP means
死亡这意味着IP方式
instruction pointer in ia32 is called a
在IA32指令指针被称为
IP and now it's called our IP just like
IP，现在它被称为我们的IP就像
the registries to be EAX now it's our IX
该登记处是EAX现在它是我们的IX
so it all it contains is the address of
所以它包含所有的地址
the currently executing instruction and
当前执行的指令和
you can it's not a register that you
你可以将它不是 一个寄存器， 你
access in a normal way but you actually
在一个正常的方式，但你实际上访问
there are tricks that you can find out
还有， 你可以找到窍门
what the value of that is so that just
什么该值是如此，只是
tells you where in the program what part
告诉你在哪里在程序 哪一部分
of the program is currently being
该方案是 目前正在
executed and then there's these things
执行，然后还有这些东西
that are called condition codes and
这被称为条件码和
we're only showing four there's actually
我们只显示了四个居然有
more like eight of them but not relevant
更像是他们八个但 不相关
to our general discussion that are all
我们一般的讨论中都
one bit flags and they get set not
一个位标志，他们得到不设置
directly but as a side effect of other
直接但 作为 其他 的 副作用
operations that take place and they're
所 发生的 ，他们是操作
the basis for which conditional
的基础，其条件
operation gets decided so let's go
操作被决定让我们去
through what those mean and there
通过什么意思那些有
they're given names but these names are
他们给出的名字，但这些名字
actually useful to memorize what they
真正有用的记住他们
mean so CF means the carry flag and that
意味着这么CF意味着进位标志和
if you think of adding two numbers think
如果你想添加的两个数字 认为
of them as two unsigned numbers and you
他们的两个无符号数，你
do the binary arithmetic and sometimes
做算术，有时
an extra one pops out of the left hand
额外的一个弹出 左手
side right that's the carry bit if you
侧右那是进位，如果你
the numbers you added sort of were too
您添加的数字排序的太
big to be contained in the the 32 or 64
大到被包含在 所述32或64个
bit or even sixteen or eight that result
位，甚至导致16或八个
and so an extra bit was generated that's
因此产生的额外位这就是
called the carry bit the zero flag is
所谓进位零标志
what it sounds like it's set if the the
这听起来像它的设置如果在
value you just computed is zero these
你刚才计算的值为零 ， 这些
are set typically by arithmetic
由算术通常设置
instructions by the way
顺便说一下说明书
the sign flag is said if the value just
如果该值的符号标志， 据说刚
computed as a 1 and the most significant
计算为1和最显著
bit meaning it's a negative value and
位意味着它是一个负值，
the ole flag overflow flag is a tooth
在OLE标志溢出标志 是 牙齿
compliment version of overflow so in
溢出的恭维版本，以便在
particular if you remember from data web
特别是如果你的数据网络记得
how do you know us if addition of two
你怎么知道我们是否添加了两个
values is overflowed it's if the signs
值溢出是如果症状
of the operands are the same but the
操作数是相同的 ，但
sign of the result is different than
结果的符号是不同于
that
那
so either you added two positive numbers
所以无论你增加了两个正 数
and got a negative result that was a
并得到了否定的结果，这是 一个
positive overflow or you added two
积极的溢出或者你加了两个
negative numbers and got a negative
负数并 得到了负
result that's negative overflow
结果是负溢出
you can't overflow up the two arguments
你不能溢出了两个参数
are of opposite signs right so those
符号相反权利，使那些
four flags get set as the sort of normal
四个标志被置作为排序的正常
activity by many of the instructions not
许多人的指示不活动
by our friend the le.a instruction which
我们的朋友的le.a指令，
I mentioned is kind of a quirky
我提到的是怎样的一个古怪的
instruction that GCC really likes a lot
指令GCC真的喜欢了很多
and you'll see it in a lot of places but
你会看到它在很多地方 ，但
in general and most of the time those
一般来说， 大部分时间这些
flags get completely ignored because who
标志得到完全忽略，因为 谁
cares right a but they do show up at
在乎权利 ，但他们出现在
various points when you're doing
当你做的不同点
conditional operations so there's some
有条件的操作，以便有一些
special instructions whose only effect
特别说明 ，其 唯一的作用
is to set condition codes and the one
是设置条件码和一个
that you'll see is especially it's
你会看到，尤其 是
called compare CMP and by the way the
所谓比较 CMP和方式的
the queue at the end of these is all
在这些端部的队列 是所有
just a reflection of their operating on
只是他们的工作的反思
64-bit words quadword as I said so the
64位字四字正如 我所说所以
comparison is sort of like a subtraction
比较是有点像 减法
instruction except that you don't you
除了你没有， 你的指令
don't do anything with the result
不与结果做任何事
normal subtraction instruction is like X
正常减法指令是如X
minus equals y it will read two numbers
减去等于Ÿ它会读取两个数字
but then it will store the result
但随后将存储结果
wherever X is stored but compare just
无论X存储，但只是比较
takes these two values does a
取这 两个值做了
subtraction and doesn't do anything with
减法 ，不会做任何事
the result but it will set it's these
结果，但它会设置 它的这些
four condition flags and
4个 状况标志和
just a few things to keep in mind that
只是几 件事情 要记住 ，
are often will be sources of confusion
往往将是混乱 的来源
is remember that the arguments in the
是记得 在参数
way we write them in machine code is the
我们写他们 的 机器 代码的方法是
opposite of what you'd expect by the way
你会的 方式 期望相反
I somebody asked me last time there's
我有人问我最后 一次有
another there's sort of two dialects of
另一个有几分 两种 方言 的
assembly code used on x86 machines
在x86机器上使用的汇编代码
there's one that's used by Intel and
有一个 的二手由英特尔和
Microsoft and we don't use it and then
微软与我们不使用 它，然后
there's the one use that sort of used by
有一个用那种使用
Linux systems and that's the one we use
Linux系统，这就是我们使用的一个
and they're different and one of the
和他们不同 ，的一个
quirks of them is they write their
他们的怪癖是他们自己写的
arguments in in different orders so it
参数在不同的顺序，因此
will drive you crazy reading trying to
会让你发疯 的阅读尝试
read if you're familiar with one it's
阅读如果你熟悉一个很
like if you've ever tried to drive a car
如果你曾经 试图 开车 像
on the wrong side of the road you often
在 道路 上的 错误的一边 ，你 经常
will crash you do bad things um so
会崩溃，你做坏事嗯所以
that's just an aside that what I find by
这只是顺便说一句什么我找到
the way when I'm looking at code and I
当我在看代码，我的方式
see a compare instruction I actually
看到一个比较指令其实我
write as a comment of compare of the two
写成的两个比较评论
but I flipped the order so that I'm sure
但我翻的 顺序，这样我敢肯定
that I sort of keep in my mind what the
我有点守 在我心中是什么
comparison was up and so these flags get
比较上升了，因此这些标志得到
set according to the rules of
根据规则设定
subtraction and so it turns out that the
减法，所以它原来，
carry flag and the overflow flag you
进位标志和溢出标志你
have to do to flip your sense of what
必须做翻转你的感觉是什么
happened because it's a subtraction
发生，因为它是一个减法
rather than addition but it's the same
而不是加法，但它是相同的
general idea so that sort of shows you
一般的想法， 这样 排序显示你
one particular one and another
一个特定的一个 和另一
instruction that you'll see whose only
指令你会看到他们的唯一
purpose in the world is to to set
目的在世界上是设置
condition flags condition codes is the
条件标志条件代码 是
test instruction and this is typically
测试指令，这通常是
used to compare as you think it's when
用于比较，你认为这是当
you have two values and you want to
你有两个值，你想
compare them to each other and the test
他们互相比较和测试
is if you really just have one value and
是，如果你真的只是有一个值 和
you want to see what it's like is it
你想看看是什么感觉是
zero is it negative those are the main
零 是负 的那些是主要的
things you care about in fact that's the
你 其实 关心的事情是这样的
only thing you can determine but just
只有你自己才能决定，但只是一点
because I guess they had they had sort
因为我想他们有他们的排序
of a possibility of having two arguments
的 具有两个参数的 可能性
to the
到
so they decided well let's to go ahead
所以他们决定好，让我们继续前进
and do it how do you have two arguments
并做到这一点你怎么有两个参数
to a test instruction what's and the two
到测试指令， 什么是和两个
results and then test that value so what
结果，然后测试值等什么
you typically see is a test where both
您通常看到的是一个测试，这两个
arguments are the same so test q % RI X
参数是相同的，所以试验Q％RI X
comma % RI x where so that you're just
逗号％RI x， 其中，这样你只是
any register to itself and one property
任何寄存器本身 和一个属性
the end operation is it's what they call
最终操作是这是他们叫什么
item potent adding ending two things the
项目有力添加结束 两件事
same things together gives you that same
同样的东西放在一起给你同样的
time
时间
so we can see these and now so I told
所以我们可以看到这些，现在让我告诉
you that's how the condition codes get
你是这样的条件代码怎么弄
set now how do you actually read them
现在设置你如何 真正阅读
how do you make use of them well there's
你如何使用它们以及有
two in principle you can actually
两个原则，你其实可以
extract and get the condition code
提取并获得条件码
values directly out of this special
值直接出这个特殊的
status register but that's very unusual
状态寄存器但这是非常不寻常
to do that what's more common is you
要做到这一点 更重要的是常见的就是 你
either try to read it in and set a 1-bit
无论是尝试读取它，并设置1位
flag based on the result in a reg some
标志基础上，结果在一个reg一些
other register or you try and do a
其他寄存器或者你尝试做一个
conditional branch so the first example
条件分支所以与第一示例
where you try to read it in a way that
在您尝试的方式来阅读这
you can make use of it is done with the
你可以利用它与 done
set instruction and you'll see there's a
指令集 ，你会看到有 一个
whole range of set instructions of but
全范围的设定指令，但
their only difference is really just
它们 唯一的区别其实只是
what the condition they're setting based
什么条件他们设定来
on so the what a set instruction does is
在这样的什么一组指令的作用是
it sets a single byte of a single
它设置了一个单一的单字节
register to either 1 or 0 and the the
寄存器为1或0， 并且所述
basis for whether it sets it to one or
对于是否将其设置为一个 或基础
to zero is a based on what the condition
零是基于条件是什么
codes are in essence what's the what
代码在 本质上有什么什么
happened your most recent instruction
碰巧最近的指令
beforehand was it an arithmetic
事先是它的算术
instruction or a set instruction or a
指令或一组指令或
test instruction or a compare
测试指令或比较
instruction and as you can see there's
指令，正如你可以看到有
they're all based on some logical
他们都基于某种逻辑
combination of these condition codes
这些条件码的组合
that correspond to what the names imply
对应于名字所暗示的是什么
so for example the set s instruction is
因此，例如集合S指令是
true if the sign flag is true meaning
真如果符号标志是真谛
that the most recent result was negative
，最近结果为阴性
and there's other ones in less than less
并有 少 其他的 小于
than or equal to our T's complement
小于或 等于 我们 T的 补码
comparisons and they have to take into
比较他们必须考虑到
consideration did the most recent result
考虑所做的 最新结果
cause an overflow or not because that
导致溢出或不是因为
will affect the result of the comparison
会影响比较结果
so that's part of the reason we tortured
所以这是我们 折磨的原因 之一
you with understanding two's complement
你理解补
arithmetic and how you compare
算术以及如何比较
dalts and making you understand the
dalts，让你明白
bit-level behavior so that you can
位级行为，这样 就可以
understand what these instructions do
了解这些指示
so we're cruel but we have a reason for
所以我们很残忍 ，但我们有一个理由
our cruelty so you say one bite how do
我们的残酷 所以你说一口怎么办
you deal with one bite well here's
你对付一口好这里的
another thing we didn't tell you yet and
另一件事，我们没有告诉你还没有 和
we're going to keep telling you more
我们要不断告诉 你更多
stuff over and over again it turns out
东西一遍又一遍 的 事实证明
for every one of these sixteen registers
对于这些 16个寄存器 中的每一个
you can directly set the lowest order
您可以直接设置最低阶
bite of it to either 0 or 1 and it won't
它咬为0或1， 它不会
affect it turns out it doesn't affect
影响事实证明它 不影响
any of the other 7 bites of that
任何的，其他7个 叮咬
register so and they all have Corky
登记，他们都有 科基
names the L means below in there so
名称L的有以下手段，使
here's an example of using putting all
这里使用的将 所有的例子
this together to do something that
这一起做一些事情，
vaguely useful suppose that I want a
隐约有用的假设，我想
function GT that will take two numbers
功能GT，将采取两个数字
and compare them and set the result
并加以比较，并设置结果
return result value of 1 if X is greater
返回的 1结果值 如果X是 更大
than Y and 0 otherwise
除Y， 否则 为0
and so here's the assembly code with
所以这里的用汇编代码
some tabbing problems
一些黏合问题
success getting bugs me or that
成功让我的错误 或
I might not want to try and do this
我可能不会想 尝试这样做
Oh No I will fix this later anyways it's
哦，不，我会解决这个问题 以后反正 是
not the end of the world normally an
世界不是结束正常的
assembly code one thing you've noticed
汇编代码一件事你已经注意到了
is that the instructions are indented
是该指令是缩进
via tab space and the only thing that's
通过标签的空间，这是唯一的事情
way over in the left margin or label so
一路过来的 左边空白处或标签，以便
this is just sort of this what the the
这仅仅是几分这个什么的
assembler is actually quite tolerant of
汇编其实是相当宽容的
formatting things but this isn't the way
格式化的东西，但不是这种方式
it normally looks so anyways the point
它通常看起来如此反正点
is there's a comparing the one rule that
是有一个比较一个规则
you need to understand about procedure
您需要了解程序
is isn't so the first argument is passed
是不是这样的第一个参数传递
in register RDI
寄存器RDI
and the second and register RS I and
以及第二和寄存器RS I和
that if I'm going to return a result
如果我要返回结果
from a function I do that by storing it
从功能我这样做，将它存储
and register our ax before I return so
并注册 我们的斧头才返回如此
the first instruction compares these two
第一指令比较这两个
and you notice how I flip the order that
你注意到我如何翻转的顺序
it says RSI which is why an RD I which
它说，RSI这 就是 为什么我RD其
is X but when I annotate it I say X to Y
是X但是当 我将其标注为我说，X到Y
so that I mentally am thinking in the
让 我精神上 我在思考
order that the actual comparison is made
下令实际做出比较
rather than the way they're listed so I
而不是这样，他们会上市，所以我
always do that when I'm looking at code
总是这样，当我在看代码
to help me flip those two around and
帮我翻转这两个四周，
then here's our instruction so that
那么这里是我们的指令，使得
compare instruction set these four
比较指令集这四个
condition code register x' and now the
条件码寄存器x”和现在的
set G says now set this single byte
集合G说，现在设置这个单字节
register the lowest byte of our ax to Z
注册我们的 斧头到Z 的最低字节
1 if the reason the result was the
1，如果该原因的结果是
comparison was greater so according to
比较是更大的，从而根据
this this rule
这此规则
and and the effect of that was to set
并与该效果设置
just as one bite of this eight byte
只是因为这 一个 八 字节的一个咬
register to either zero or one now my
注册 零个或一个 现在我的
problem is that these remaining seven
问题是， 这些剩下的 七个
bytes have whatever happened to be there
字节都无论发生在那里
before and I want it to be all zeros so
之前，我希望它是全零如此
the the way it does it is a bit weird
在它的方式是有点怪
there's an instruction called move with
有一个名为移动的指令
zero extension byte too long now you get
零扩展字节现在太长你
to know these better if with time okay
要知道这些更好，如果有时间好吗
um and what what that means is you can
嗯，什么这是什么意思是，你可以
actually copy a byte from any place like
实际上从任何地方复制字节像
the low order byte of some other
一些其他的低位字节
register into a new register and you'll
注册到一个新的寄存器，你会
put put zeros to the left of it that's
把置零到它的左边 那
what they mean by zero extension that
他们的意思是 零扩展
seems logical but one thing you'll
似乎顺理成章，但有一件事，你会
notice is the destination here is EAX
通知是 这里 的 目的是EAX
which you'll recall although it doesn't
你还记得虽然它不
show here that's the lower 32 bits of
在这里展示这的低32位
register are a X and then you'd say well
寄存器是 一个 X，然后你会说好
that only got me halfway there right how
只有让我 中途 有 怎样的权利
do I make sure the upper 32 bits are set
我要确保高32位被设置
to zero well one of the weird quirks of
零 井的奇怪怪癖之一
x86 64 is for any computation where the
86 64 是用于任何计算，其中
result is a 32-bit result it will add
结果是一个32位结果，将添加
zeros to the remaining 32 bits of the
零来的剩余的32位
register and it's different for example
注册和它的例如不同
the byte level operations only affect
字节级操作只会影响
the bikes the two byte or operations
自行车两个字节或操作
like what you'd have if the data type
就像你有什么，如果数据类型
were short only affect those two bytes
中短只影响 这两个字节
but the four byte instructions set the
但四个字节指令集
upper bytes to zero and that was some
高位字节到零， 这是一些
somebody at AMD and I don't know who it
有人在 AMD，我不 知道是谁
is decided this was a good idea and it
决定这是一个好 主意 ，它
might be a good idea but it's really
可能是一个好主意 ，但它 确实
confusing but that's something you'll
混乱，但这东西你会
have to just sort of remember in the
有只是有点记得在
back your mind when you see things like
回你的 头脑，当你看到 喜欢 的东西
this
这个
so the effect of this instruction is to
所以该指令的效果是
take this one bite result which is the
借此一咬结果这是
lower door bite of register our ax copy
注册我们的 斧头副本 的 下 门咬
it to the same place as it already is
它在同一个地方，因为它已经是
but then set the remaining seven bytes
但随后设置其余7个字节
to zero which is what we want so you'll
到零，这是我们想的 那么你会
see this pattern quite often question
看到这种模式常常质疑
got it
得到它了
okay so now that's sort of sometimes I
好了，现在的排序有时 我
want to do this I just want to get a one
要做到这一点， 我 只是想获得一个
bit flag as a result of the comparison
比特标志作为比较的结果
but more generally I want to do
但更普遍的我想要做的
something with that information and not
一些与该 信息 ，而 不是
just set one bit so the simplest version
只需设置一个位，因此最简单的版本
is what about a conditional and if and
是关于什么的 一个条件 ，如果和
possibly an else well that's done by
可能的其他嗯，这是通过做
this actually two ways to do it so we'll
其实这两种方法可以做到这一点，所以我们会
go through the sort of general purpose
经过排序 的通用
traditional way and then we'll show the
传统的方式，然后我们会 展示
more specialized newer way and we'll
更专业的方式更新，我们将
compare those so the traditional way is
比较这些使传统的 方式是
to use what's known as a jump
用什么 作为一个跳
instruction and a jump instruction
指令和跳转指令
normally instructions execute in a
通常的指令执行在
particular order just like when you're
特定的顺序只是当你喜欢
writing a program and you write a series
写一个程序，你写一个系列
of statements they execute one after the
声明他们执行一个后
next a jump instruction is the way you
下一跳转指令就是这样，你
can go from wherever you are to
可以去的地方，你是
someplace else and either skip over some
别的地方，要么跳过一些
instructions or jump back to some other
指令或跳回其他一些
a previous position or wherever and
先前的位置或其它地方和
there's two kinds of jumps ones that are
有2种跳那些是
unconditional where there's several
无条件那里 有几个
kinds but an unconditional jump means
种但无条件 跳转手段
when I say jump you jump but there's
当我说跳你跳，但有
others conditional jumps that will
其他条件跳转即会
actually only do that jumping if the
实际上只有做到这一点跳跃如果
condition codes are set appropriately
条件码被设定适当
and you'll see that the names of these
你会看到，这些名字
jump instructions are the same as the
跳转指令是一样的
set instructions with the same
用同一套指令
conditions so there's a variety of
条件，有多种
different reasons that the program may
不同的原因 ，该计划可能
be given to either jump or not jump
给予要么跳或不跳
so I'm going to use this one example to
所以我打算用这个 例子来
show you several different versions of
告诉你几种不同 的版本
it and like everything you'll see here
它和喜欢的一切，你会看到这里
these particular programs aren't that
这些特定的程序都不是
useful but they illustrate ideas so
有用的，但它们说明了 这样 的想法
imagine I wanted to compute the the
想象我想计算的
difference of two values and then take
两个值的差，然后采取
their absolute value so there's various
其绝对值所以有各种
ways you could imagine doing it by the
方法，你 能想象 在 这样做
way I'm going to do it is decide to
办法，我要做到这一点是决定
either subtract Y from X or X from Y
无论是 从由Y X或X中减去y
depending on the relative values of
根据的相对值
those two and of course the astute
这两个，当然精明
observer will notice that this has
观察者会发现，这有
problems if you have a team in somewhere
问题，如果你有在地方队
if the result because there's no
如果结果因为没有
absolute value but we're not going to
绝对值但 我们不打算
worry about that table so in other words
担心表 ，以便换句话说
I just want to say if X is greater than
我只想说，如果X 大于
Y then I wanted to track Y from X and if
y时， 我想 从X， 如果 跟踪ÿ
X is less than or equal to Y I want to
X 小于或 等于YI 希望
subtract X from 1 and here's the code
用1减去X 和下面的代码
for it where the blue and the red or
它其中蓝色和红色或
color coding the different parts of it
颜色编码它的不同部分
so here you see the compare instruction
所以在这里你看到的比较指令
and again I've written them out in the
又一次我写出来的
reverse order to help me keep track of
反向为了帮我记录下来 的
what the comparison is and it says I'm
什么比较，它说我
going to compare x and y and if X is
要比较X和Y，如果X是
less than or equal to Y I want to jump
小于 或等于YI想跳
to a location specified by this label l4
通过这个 标签L4 指定的位置
and so in general in assembly code if
因此在一般在汇编代码，如果
you give a name and then a colon what's
你给一个名字，然后一个 冒号 什么
to the left of that is called a label
到了左侧被称为标签
and it's just a tag that that only
它只是一个标记，只有
visible in the assembly code it's not
在汇编代码中看到它不是
actually in the object code that will
实际上在对象的代码，将
later I'll be used to compute an address
我稍后会 被用来 计算一个地址
for determining that will encode what
用于确定 将什么编码
where this jump will actually land when
其中，这一跳将实际降落时
you're looking at assembly code one of
你看汇编代码中的一个
the features it provides is a little bit
它提供的功能是一点点
easier way to understand it than to look
更简单的方法去理解它 ，而不是看
at addresses and so it just tells you to
在地址，所以它只是告诉你
be looking at that the jump would occur
在看会发生跳跃
to this position
这个位置
and what you'll see here is the in these
什么，你会在这里看到的是在这些
two branches the blue code versus the
两个分支 的蓝色代码兑
red what you're doing is in one case
红色，你正在做的事情是在一种 情况下
subtracting Y from X here you move X
从X减去这里y您移动X
into our ax and you subtract Y from it
到我们的 斧头和你从它减去y
and here you do the opposite you're
在这里，你做 你的对面
subtracting X from Y and in this case so
从Y，在这种情况下减去X等等
in the first case you'll make the jump
在第一种情况下，你会做跳跃
if X is less than or equal to Y you'll
如果X 小于或 等于y你会
compact Y from X and you'll do a return
紧凑值Y X， 你会做一回
and you remember that I don't have to do
你记住， 我没有做
anything special to return a value back
任何特殊的返回值回
from a function all I have to do is
从功能的所有我需要做的就是
stick it and register IX and the calling
坚持下去并注册 IX和主叫
function will know that's where to find
功能会知道这是在哪里可以找到
the return value so here it does a rep
返回值，以便在这里做一个代表
and here it does the subtraction and it
在这里它做减法，它
simply does a return directly from that
干脆直接从做一回
part of it so it's a pretty
它的一部分，所以这是一个非常
straightforward piece of code but you
简单的代码，但你
can see it's using this jumping to
可以看到它使用此跳转到
create two different parts of code that
创建的代码的两个不同部分
get executed under two different
在 两种不同的 得到 执行
conditions question
条件问题
what's that I'm sorry I didn't hear you
那是什么我很抱歉，我没听到你
oh well there's a couple things one is
哦 也有几件事情之一就是
you want the result to end up in our X
你想要的结果在我们的X结束
right and remember the subtract
右记住 减法
instruction structions are just two
指令structions只是 两个
argument instructions there that you
参数说明那里，你
take two values and then you the ones
取两个值，然后你的那些
the second argument the destination
第二个参数的目的地
argument you overwrite what was there
争论则会覆盖那儿有什么
with the new result so this is a pretty
有新的结果，所以这是一个非常
typical pattern you'll see of you move
典型的模式，你会看到你移动
some value into a register and then you
一些值到寄存器，然后你
into our ax is very common and then you
进入我们的斧头是很常见的 ，然后你
do some arithmetic operation with that
做一些运算
register as a destination to kind of
注册为目的地 来样
update it if it's like if you were
更新它，如果它就像 如果你是
writing and see if all the time you had
写，看看是否所有的时间你有
to write sort of X plus equals something
写排序X加等于 什么
X minus equals and that all your
X减等于和 你的所有
arithmetic had to be expressed in those
算术不得不在那些中表达
terms
条款
okay so it's fun to look at assembly
好了 ，所以它的乐趣 ，看装配
code for about five minutes and then you
约五分钟， 然后你 的代码
get sick of it so one thing to sort of
生病的 这么一件事情 进行排序
present these same ideas but give it in
目前这些相同的想法 ，但给它
a little bit more abstract form is to
多一点点抽象的形式是
write it and see but in a form of C that
写一下，看看但在C的形式，
looks a lot like assembly code and in
看起来像汇编代码，并在很多
particular one of the features of C that
的C的特征的特定一个
is not generally advertised is there's a
一般不做广告是有一个
statement called go-to and you can put
声明呼吁去到你可以把
labels in your code and you can tell the
在 你的代码的标签， 你可以告诉
program that if something happens then
程序，如果有事则
you want to jump to that part of the
你要跳转到 的 那 部分
program so it looks a lot like that
程序，所以它看起来很像 是
assembly code right that you saw jump jl
你看到跳JL汇编代码的权利
e instead of what this says it's like
电子商务不是什么该说这就像
i'm doing a test and then if the test is
我正在 做一个测试，然后如果测试
which in this case i call it end test
在这种情况下我称之为 端测试
because it's the opposite of the test
因为它是测试的对面
that's in the original program and if
这是在原来的程序 ，如果
that end test condition holds i want to
为此测试条件成立 ，我想
jump to another part of the program i'm
跳转到 节目 我是 另一部分
calling else and you notice i uppercase
调用别的，你注意到我大写
that because it's not the actual else of
因为它不是实际的其他
a an if-then-else and certainly if this
一个一个if-then-else和肯定，如果这
one is well actually to be most accurate
一个非常其实是最准确的
i should have simply said return result
我应该 只是简单地 说 返回结果
from this point this codes a little bit
从这个角度这个 代码 一点点
out of date so I should have said return
过时的，所以我应该说回报
result but another version would be to
结果，但另一种说法，是
have done a goto down to here and return
已经做了跳转到此处并返回
the result from there and you'll see
从那里，你会看到结果
different compilers generate in
不同的编译器 生成
different forms so I'm going to
不同形式的所以我要去
typically use this way of presenting
通常使用呈现这样
code just so that you can look at and
代码只是让你可以看看和
understand what these control structures
了解这些控制结构
look like without having to sort of
看起来像，而无需进行排序
scrutinize the low-level assembly code
细察低级汇编代码
instructions
说明
so we consider take this question yes I
所以我们考虑采取这个问题是 我
think there's a homework or practice
想有一个家庭作业或练习
problems of exactly that sort so in
究竟那种所以问题
general you could do it neither way and
一般来说，你可以做到这一点既不方式
why the compiler picks one versus the
为什么编译器挑选一个相对于
other is I think it's a completely
另 一种是我认为这是一个完全
arbitrary decision but consistently I
武断的决定，但我始终
found GCC does it this way
发现GCC确实是这样
okay so what sort of talking sort of
谈排序的好了，什么样的
imagine you're writing a compiler how
想象一下你正在写一个编译器如何
would you take this special case I just
你会采取这种特殊的情况下，我 只是
showed and generalize it into a rule for
表明它概括成一个规则
compiling if-then-else expressions and
编译IF-THEN-ELSE表达式 和
I'm going to use the version of in see
我会 在 看到 使用的 版本
the question mark : version where you
问号 ：版本，你
kind of encapsulate that whole
一种封装了整个
conditional is a single expression
条件是一个单一表达式
rather than the statement but you can
而不是语句，但你 可以
understand that these rules would be the
了解这些规则将是
same in either case so imagine in
同样在这两种情况下如此想象
general you had a C code where there's a
一般来说，你有一个C代码，其中有一个
test controlling whether to return the
测试控制是否返回
result of one expression or another and
一种表达的结果或其它，并
this is what my ABS diff code would look
这是我的 ABS 差异代码看起来
like if I wrote it in that form and so
就像如果我以 这种形式等写的
in general what we can say is what what
一般来说，我们可以说什么就是什么什么
we'll do is we'll come take the test and
我们要做的是，我们会来参加考试和
tit and invert it and say if that test
针锋相对并 倒转 ，并说，如果该测试
is not true then we will so if n test is
是不是真的那么我们会因此如果n 测试
true then we will jump to some part of
那么真的，我们将跳转 到的某些部分
the code where we've compiled the code
这里我们编译的代码的代码
for the else expression and if the that
对于其他 的表达，如果说
test fails here so that the original
这里测试失败使原来
test condition holds then we'll stick in
测试条件成立那么我们会坚持在
whatever code it takes to to compute the
任何代码才能计算
done expression and then we'll merge
做了表达，然后我们将合并
back together in the case you saw where
回到一起的情况下 ，你看到哪里
it's just a single little function we
它只是一个小功能，我们
can just call a rep here and get out of
可以就在这里所说的代表，让出
the thing but if this is one line of
事情 ，但如果这是一条线
code
码
then there's a whole bunch of lines
再有就是线路的一大堆
after that typically you want to merge
之后 ， 通常要合并
back together again and continue from
再聚首，并从继续
there and so that's what this shows all
那里，所以这就是这个显示所有
I'll finish by going to whatever comes
我将要一切以完成
afterwards so this is a way I like to
事后所以这是一种方法，我 喜欢
you know although we're not writing
你知道，虽然 我们不是在写
compilers in this course I think it
在这个过程中的编译器，我认为它
helps to to think in terms of general
帮助想在 一般 条款
rules of how a compiler would translate
的编译器将如何转化规则
C code into assembly code so that when
C代码到汇编代码，使得当
you see that assembly code you'll
你看到的汇编代码，你会
recognize these patterns and know what
识别这些模式并了解
they mean question so after you go to
他们的意思是这样 的问题 后，你去
the else clause doesn't like fall
else 子句 不喜欢秋天
through to the John yes yes so just as
通过对 约翰是是这样，就像
we saw yes in general it like here it
我们一般是看到了它喜欢在这里
would fall through to the done good
将始终陷入做了 很好的
question
题
okay so that's one version of
好了，所以这是一个版本
conditional that's the most general way
有条件的，这是最普遍的方式
and the way it used to always be done
它使用的方式总是做
but there's another approach that you'll
但还有另一种方法，你会
see fairly common in code it's sort of
看到代码相当普遍这有点
an optimization called conditional move
所谓有条件移动优化
and it's bit non-intuitive from a
它是从一个有点不直观
software developers perspective of why
为什么 软件 开发者的角度
you'd ever want to do this the basic
你会永远想这样做的基本
idea is I'm going to compute both the
想法是我要计算这两个
then and the elks the values they'd
然后和麋鹿的价值观，他们会
produce and only after that I choose
生产，之后才是我选择
which one I use
哪一个我用
so it seems wasteful but it actually
如此看来浪费， 但实际上
turns out to be more efficient if there
原来 是 ，如果有更有效
are fairly simple computations and the
是相当简单的计算和
reason of that is and we'll see a little
那原因是，我们会看到一个小
bit more when we talk about performance
当我们谈论性能更加 位
optimization a modern processor is a
优化现代处理器是
little like a an oil tanker sailing in
有点像在油轮航行
the sea meaning that it plows along in a
海 这 意味着它在沿着犁
certain direction and it really is hard
某些方向，那 真的是难
to get it to stop or to turn so that you
让它停止或开启， 让 你
say what are you talking about but think
说什么你在说什么 ，但认为
of an instruction sequences you know the
指令序列的你知道
ocean of code that you're cruising
代码的海洋，你巡航
through and these things can just fly
通过和这些东西 只是飞
through a straight sequence of code
通过的代码的直序列
because they are they do what they call
因为他们是他们做他们所谓的
pipelining meaning they start bringing
流水线这意味着他们将开始
in parts of one instruction before
在前一个指令的部分
they're done with the next and actually
他们的下一个和实际完成
go up to depths of 20 or more
上升到 20个或 更多 的深度
instructions deep of how far had they're
深多远了他们的指令
working to defecting forward and future
努力 向前背叛和未来
instructions while finishing up the ones
指令同时完成了的那些
that still remain so that's my ocean
这仍然让我的海洋
line of my tanker analogy but all of a
我的油轮类比线，但所有的
sudden you come and then what happens
突然你来，然后 会发生什么
when they hit a branch they'll try to
当他们打了一个分支，他们会尽力
guess called branch prediction and guess
想叫分支预测和猜测
where is this kind of branch going to go
其中这种分支要去
where you know
在那里，你知道
well the conditional branch should be
良好条件分支应该是
taken or is it going to fall through and
采取抑或是要落空 和
they're pretty good at that they're good
他们很擅长，他们是很好的
at it ninety ninety eight percent of the
在 的 这 90百分之八九十
time so they can even anticipate suit it
时间，以便 他们可以 预见，即使 它适合
curves in the road my analogy is
在路上我的比喻是曲线
breaking down
打破
and start going in that direction and as
并开始在这个方向和打算
long as they get it right it's very
只要他们得到它的权利是非常
efficient but if they get it wrong it's
有效的，但如果他们弄错了它的
as if you have to stop the thing back it
因为如果你必须停止回事情它
up turn the other way start again and
向上转弯的其他方式 重新开始和
that can take 40 instructions 40 clock
可以采取 40说明40时钟
cycles so to do in bed situation so and
这样的循环在床上的情况这样做，
this is pretty common if you think of
这就是 ，如果你认为的 很常见
like an absolute value can you predict
像一个绝对值可以预测
whether a value is going to be positive
值是否将是积极的
or negative if not usually so about half
或负，如果不是这样，通常的一半左右
the time whatever you guess you're going
无论你想你的时候要去
to guess wrong so these are conditional
猜测错了，所以这是有条件的
move instructions it turns out it's much
移动指令事实证明这是多
easier to just plow through compute both
容易只是通过计算两个犁
and then at the last minute all you have
然后在最后一分钟 你有
to do is move a value into a register or
做的是移动值到寄存器或
not and that doesn't require stopping
不和不需要停止
the whole processor and making this turn
整个处理器，使本回合中，
so that's my long explanation for and if
所以这是我的，如果长时间解释
you don't want to understand that I'll
你不想了解我
just say well just trust me it's a good
只是说好了只是相信我，这是个好
idea sometimes so the the general
有时 想法 所以一般
pattern then if I use the same idea is I
然后，模式，如果我用同样的想法是我
want to compute both results and I'll
要 计算两个结果，我会
call the result and this is an eval this
调用的结果，这是一个eval这
is eval the elks value I'll compute both
是EVAL 麋鹿价值，我会同时计算
of them I'll do my test and then this
其中我会尽我的 测试，然后这个
red thing imagine that's all done with a
红色的东西想象，一切都以done
single instruction that says I'll copy
单指令，说我会复制
the value of eval to result but only if
导致EVAL的价值，但只有当
a condition holds so that's why it's
一个条件成立所以这就是为什么它是
called a conditional move then we'll see
所谓有条件的举动然后我们会看到
this is the code by the way you saw my
这是你看到的样子我的代码
original version starting to have to
最初的版本开始有
jump back I had to explicitly tell the
跳回我必须明确地告诉
GCC don't put use conditional moves
GCC 不要把使用条件移动
because it really wants to very badly
因为它确实要 非常糟糕
and so you have to force it not to and I
所以你必须把它强制不和我
did that here
这样做，在这里
so here's the actual code then and again
所以这里的实际代码 ，然后，再
you'll see the color coding that it's
你会看到的 颜色编码 ，它的
doing both subtractions it's actually
既做减法它实际上是
doing the move and subtract move and
做移动和减去移动和
subtract so it's doing both the branches
减去所以它做两个分支
you saw before the den and the Elks
你 的书房和麋鹿 以前看到的
branch it's doing a comparison and then
分支它做一个比较 ，然后
here is the conditional move instruction
这里是条件移动指令
C move in this case the L here is not a
在这种情况下，这里的L C举动是不是
word size it's the less than or equal to
字长它比小于 或等于
a direction so in the case the that I
的方向，以便在壳体中的，我
need the red value basically you saw the
需要的红色值 基本上 你看到的
red value is stored in register RDX in
红色值被存储在寄存器RDX在
that case I will copy it into the result
这种情况下，我将它复制 到结果
register so again it's like this idea of
注册，以便再次是这样的想法
just go ahead and do everything and then
先走一步，做的一切， 然后
pick at the last end and the point is
挑在去年年底和点
that this one instruction it looks just
这一个指令， 它 看起来 就像
as far as for this processor execution
只要该处理器执行
that's sort of like a a move instruction
这有点像 一个 移动 指令
that it's fairly straightforward to do
这是相当简单的做
okay
好的
so why does it do that all the time well
那么，为什么会这样所有的 时间以及
there's a couple reasons one is that
有一对夫妇一个原因是，
might be a really really bad idea to do
可能是一个非常 非常糟糕的 主意办
both computations if you have to like
两者的计算，如果你有喜欢
crack a password in one and you know
在一个破解密码， 你知道
find the enterprise number and another
找到企业数量和另一
you probably don't want to do both of
你可能不希望 两者都 做 的
those so in general in that case and so
那些所以一般 在 这种情况下 ，因此
the and you'll notice GCC will only do
在你会发现GCC只会做
this if both branches are fairly
如果这两个分支是相当
straightforward computations that
简单计算即
they're trying to do and they sometimes
他们正在试图 做的，他们 有时
when you just plain can't do it so for
当你只是普通的不能做，所以对
example if you're using a conditional to
例如，如果您使用的是有条件的
guard whether a pointer can be
守卫指针是否可
dereferenced or not because it's a null
提领或不是因为它是一个空
pointer potentially a null pointer then
指针潜在一个空指针然后
you really don't want to try that null
你真的不想尝试空
pointer dereference just for the for as
指针引用只是为了用于为
a way to save some time and similarly if
一种方法来节省一些 时间和同样的，如果
if you could have a side-effect if the
如果你可以有如果一个副作用
result of executing either branch could
执行任一分支的结果可能
be to change some other part of the
是改变的其他部分
program state then you don't really want
程序的状态 ，那么你真的不 希望
to do that either and so the conditional
这样做，要么 等条件
move only gets used then in this
仅移动被使用，那么在这
somewhat special case that you have two
你有两个有点特例
computations relatively easy to do safe
计算比较 容易做到 安全
to do no side-effects but that happens
做没有副作用，但出现这种情况
just often enough so this is actually a
只是往往足以使这实际上是一个
worthwhile thing
值得的事情
okay so that gets us conditionals and
好了，可以让我们 和 条件语句
now let's look at loops that sort of
现在让我们来看看循环之类的
next step up in control structures and
下一步起来控制结构和
see actually has three different kinds
看到实际上有三种 不同
of loops it has a a while loop which
循环 有AA，而环路
you're familiar with and a for loop
你熟悉和一个for循环
which you're familiar with and it has a
你很熟悉，它有一个
third one which in my whole life of
第三个这在我的整个生命
writing and I've written a lot of C code
写作和我已经写了大量的C代码
in my life I've used this like about six
在我的生活中，我用这个像约六
times so but it turns out it's the
次，但事实证明 它是
simplest one to implement so we'll go
最简单的 实现 ，所以我们会去
ahead and do it so that the it's called
继续做它 ，以便 它被称为
the do-while loop and so the keyword is
在do-while循环等等 关键字
do and then there's some stuff you do
做什么，然后有一些东西，你做
that's the body of the do and then
这是该做的 身体 ，然后
there's a test at the end that tells you
有一个在告诉你结束测试
whether to keep repeating this loop so
是否继续重复这个循环 ，使
it sort of flips the normal while loop
它像是翻转正常while循环
you you have the conditional test at the
你必须 在 条件 测试
front and here you have it at the end
前，在这里你有它在最后
and so it turns out if we think in terms
所以事实证明，如果我们认为 条款
of go-to that's a pretty straightforward
的 去到这是一个非常简单的
thing to replace this with a code that
事情到了 代码 替换这 一点，
will do a test and if the test holds it
会做一个测试 ，如果测试其持有
will jump back and say okay a reacts
将跳转回来，说好一个做出反应
acute that part of the program I was
节目我是急性一部分
just in so it sets up a loop where you
只是所以它建立了一个循环，你
can think of it's literally a loop of
可以认为 它是一个字面上的环
control flow going round and round and
控制流兜兜转转， 和
by the way this is actually a semi
顺便说这其实是一种半
useful function it's called pop count
有用的功能，它被称为流行计数
sometimes how many ones are there in a
在有时有多少的人在那里
in a word of data in this case at 64-bit
在这种 情况下， 在64位 数据的一个字
word there's been some generations of
字还有的是一些代
data web where you were required to
你在哪里需要数据网络
write this function using all your
使用所有写这个功能您
favorite operations and with a fairly
最喜欢的业务，并与一个相当
small limit on operations but we're not
在操作小限制 ，但我们不
doing that today so here my point is you
这样做 ，所以今天在这里我要说的是你
see that there's a fairly
看到 有一个相当的
straightforward way of taking this
采取 这种简单的方法
particular loop and turning it into just
特别是循环，把它逼到
combination of conditional that where
的条件的组合，其中
you do is you jump back to where you
你要做的就是你跳回到你
were before and here's the actual code
术前，这里的实际 代码
for it
为了它
I won't go through all of it but you can
我不会去通过 所有的，但你 可以
believe from these annotations that it
从这些注释认为，
very closely follows the code here and
这里非常密切关注的代码，
the main thing to see is this jump if
主要 看 的 是 这个跳跃如果
not equal to label l2 and that takes you
不等于标签L2而这需要你
back to here and so the general form of
回到这里 ，因此一般形式
it then is you take a do and then this
然后，它是你需要做什么， 然后这个
part that's called the body of the loop
这就是 所谓的循环体 的一部分
and this is the test and so now you set
这是测试，因此现在你设置
up some code where you can execute the
一些代码，你可以执行
body perform the test and if the test
体进行测试，如果测试
holds you go back to the loop so a while
拥有你回去循环，使一会儿
loop is really just what I could do loop
环真的只是我能做什么循环
a do while loop except that you move the
一个做，而只是循环，你移动
test to the beginning and the only
试验开始时，唯一的
difference therefore is with a do loop
因此，不同的是用do循环
you never you don't do the test it the
你从来不这样做的测试中
first time through you're guaranteed to
第一次通过你保证
do it the first time no matter what
做第一次不管是什么
while a while loop will explicitly test
而while循环将 明确测试
even at the very beginning and and skip
即使在最开始和并跳过
over the loop if the condition doesn't
在循环，如果条件不
hold so there's two ways to generate a
持有如此有两种方式产生
code whether there's more than two ways
代码是否有 两个以上 的 方法
to generate code for a while loop but
生成的代码为 while循环，但
you'll find GCC of two uses two
你会发现GCC 两个 使用两个
different ways one is what we'll find
不同的方式之一就是我们会发现
when we use this optimization setting I
当 我们使用这种优化设置我
talked about last time called minus
谈到所谓 减去 最后一次
capital o stands for optimized aji which
资本O代表优化AJI这
means debug of course as you've already
当然意味着调试正如你已经
know there's some history to what the
知道有一些历史的东西
minus G flags means so and as I
减去 ģ标志 装置，以便当我
mentioned last time this turns out to be
上次提到的这原来 是
the perfect level of optimization for
优化的完美水平
this course where you want to be able to
这当然要能
look at machine code and understand it
看机器代码和理解
and how it relates to the C code because
和它如何与C代码，因为
it does some sort of simple
它某种简单
optimizations but it doesn't try to
优化，但它并不试图
rewrite your whole program to make it
重写你的整个程序，使它
run better whereas even with minus o 1
运行而即使减去·1更好
which is the next level in the
这是在 一个新的水平
optimization you'll find sometimes it
优化 你 有时会 发现 它
will do some pretty cool
会做一些很酷
stuff but when you actually as a program
的东西，但是当你真正作为一个程序
developer as a software developer out
开发商作为一个软件开发出来
there or you talk to companies and yes
有或者 你跟公司和肯定
what optimization level do you use
什么优化级别你使用
they'll probably say - OH - that's sort
他们可能会 说- OH -这就是排序
of the common point so usually there's
公共点的所以通常有
higher levels optimization and we're
更高水平的优化，我们
purposely backing off from that to make
特意从釜底抽薪，使
this code easier to understand so
这个代码更易于理解这样
anyways with the default optimization
反正与默认优化
we're using for this course it does a
我们使用这门课程它做了
transformation I call the jump to middle
改造我打电话跳到中间
translation these are by the way my own
翻译这些 都是顺便 说一下我自己
names you won't find them in any other
名字你不会发现他们在 任何其他
document but with the idea of it is
文档，但与 它 的想法 是
imagine again I have a while loop of
再想象我有一个while 循环
this form where there's a test in the
这种形式，其中有一个测试中
body to execute well what out the
机身很好地执行什么了
problem I have to do compared to before
问题我已经比以前做的
is some I've to execute the test before
是一些我以前执行测试
I start the first iteration of the loop
我开始 循环的第一次迭代
so the way I'll do it here is I'll just
所以我会 在这里做 的方式 是我就
jump to the middle of the what was the
跳的 是什么中间
old loop code to the test portion of
旧线圈代码的测试部
that loop and then let that test
该循环然后让 该测试
determine whether I actually enter the
确定我是否真的进入
loop itself and so this is an example of
环本身，因此这是一个例子
a go to a code version of my pop count
一去我弹出数的代码版本
function so I've written a pop count
功能，所以我写了一个流行数
function using a while loop this time it
使用while 循环这一次函数
turns out whether you do or a while loop
原来，不管你做什么或while循环
you'll get the same result in this
你会得到这样的结果相同
particular function and and you'll see
特定的功能和，你会看到
the way it looks is it it jumped to the
它的外观是它跃升到
test portion of the code and and then if
的代码，并与测试部分则如果
that holds it then actually starts in
持有那么它 实际上 在 开始
the first execution of the loop and then
的循环，然后 在第一次 执行
from there on it looks the same as the
从那里，它看起来一样的
do-while loop it just does the what was
do-while循环，它只是做的是什么
in the loop does the test jumps back to
在环做测试跳回
the beginning
开始
although and then there's a second
虽然再有第二
method which is in some ways more
方法是在某些方面 更
traditional and you'll find that if you
传统的，你会发现，如果你
use optimization one which is a fairly
利用优化其中之一是相当
useful thing to do in practice so just
有用的东西在实践中 这样 做 只是
to show you that instead of deciding
要告诉你 ，而不是决定
which one I was going to show you I
其中之一，我要告诉你我
decided to show you both and the idea of
决定向您展示这两个和的想法
that is to do it essentially to take a
这是 做 它基本上是采取
while loop and turn it into do-while
而循环并把它变成做，而
loop but introducing a conditional
循环，但引入的有条件
beforehand that would essentially guard
事先将基本守卫
your entrance to the loop so you do an
你的入口处循环，使你做一个
initial test and if that false then you
最初的测试，如果是假的，那么你
skip over the loop all together
跳过环路一起
otherwise it's performed like a do-while
否则，就会像一个做同时进行
loop and so that has a fairly
环等具有相当
straightforward translation into code
直接转换成代码
and that again it looks a little
并再次显得有些
different from before that it has an
从 它具有以往不同
initial test but then it looks like a
最初的测试，但那么它 看起来像 一个
do-while loop
do-while循环
and so I won't show you the assembly
所以我不会告诉你的 组件
versions of those but if you if you look
这些版本，但如果你，如果你看
at it actually the code is all in
在实际的代码是在所有
directories that are linked to your
链接到 您的目录
class directory to the class webpage so
类目录的类 网页，以便
you can actually look at the code and
实际上你可以看看代码和
you'll see that it follows exactly the
你会看到，它遵循完全
way I'm describing it and then a third
这样我描述它，然后第三
kind of loop is the for loop which in C
类型的循环是for循环，其用C
is actually a very powerful very general
其实是一个很强大很一般
type of thing and so it's very commonly
型的东西，所以它是非常 普遍
used but you can see that the for loop
使用 ，但 你 可以看到，在for循环
has four components to it has an
有四个组成部分 它有一个
initialization as a test has a rule for
初始化的测试有一个规则
doing an update in case as a way to
在这样的情况下更新，以此来
continue the loop and then it has the
继续循环，然后它有
body of the loop and so here's the
循环体，因此这里的
version of my pop calc function where
我的弹出钙函数，其中的版本
I'm just going through all the bits in
我只是通过在所有位
the word extracting them out and adding
该单词提取出来，并加入
them accumulating them to be the result
他们积累他们就可以出结果
so ripping apart this for you'll see
所以翻录除了这个你会看到
that these four blocks of of the loop
是的环路的这四个 块
corresponds the initialization is to set
对应的初始化 设置
equal to zero the test is to compare I
等于零的测试是比较我
to the word size which I've set here to
而我在这里设置为字长
be eight ton so however many bytes are
为八个 吨左右但多少字节
in an int multiply that by 8 to get the
在 一个int乘上8来获得
word size and then the update is I plus
字的大小，然后更新是我加
plus and then the body is this stuff
加上然后 身体就是 这个东西
that's within the brackets here so I can
这就是括号内这里，所以我可以
think of that in general one one general
想到 这一点，一般一个一个一般
way to think about a for loop and see is
方式来思考一个for循环和看到的是
by this rule that will turn a for loop
此规则将变成一个for循环
into a while loop and so what it says is
成while循环，因此它说什么是
I first do the initialization and then I
我先做初始化，然后我
do a loop where I I guard it with this
做一个循环，我我这个保护它
test and then what I keep doing is
测试，然后我继续这样做是
executing the body and then performing
执行主体 ，然后进行
whatever
随你
date there is and then continuing with
到目前为止还，然后 用 继续
the test so that sort of the semantics
测试使 某种语义
the the definition of the behavior of a
的行为的定义
for loop and see so I can take my
for循环， 看这样我就可以把我的
different pieces of my for loop and say
for循环不同的部分我的 ，说
well okay I'll take that rule and use it
好吧好吧，我承担了规则，并用它
to pack them in to form a while work and
收拾他们，形成同时工作，
of course you know that you can sort of
当然，你知道，你可以排序的
go between those two as somewhat a
这两个之间去为一个有点
matter of taste whether a given loop
品味的问题是否在指定循环
should be written using a for loop or a
应该使用一个循环或写
while loop so one reason why it's
而循环，这样一个原因，它是
actually useful to do the - oh one
真正有用的 做-一个哦
optimization I talked to you about is
优化 我跟大家介绍的就是
it's fairly common for the initial test
它是最初的 测试相当普遍
to be trivially trivially true so for
是平凡的平凡真实所以对于
example in here if I equals zero and I'm
例如，在这里，如果我等于零 ，我
comparing it to the word size which
它比较字尺寸
would typically be 32
通常将32
well that test is true that's a certain
清楚，测试结果是真，这是一个特定的
thing and so what you'll see is that the
的事情，所以你会看到 的 是，
compiler can figure that out and just
编译器可以明白这一点 ，只是
throw away this guarding code that would
扔掉这个守卫码会
have to be there otherwise so so that
必须有 ，否则这样使
that I believe is the main reason why
我认为这是最主要的原因 ，
this is the transformation that gets
这是得到改造
used to the oh one optimization level is
用的哦一个优化级别
that often times it doesn't need this
那很多时候并不 需要这个
initial test
初步测试
okay so now I'm going to finish up with
好吧所以现在我 要 与 完成了
what's in its immediately the loop stuff
什么是在 它的直接环路的东西
is sort of what you'd expect if you were
是那种 如果你是 你所期望
to have to you know turn a C code into
有你 知道把一个C代码到
something very low-level where all you
一些很低级的，所有你
could do is jumps and test well maybe
可以做的是跳跃和测试以及可能
that's obvious but maybe not the switch
这是显而易见的，但也许不是开关
statement on the other hand is a totally
在另一方面语句是完全
different beast and I want to show you
不同的野兽 ，我想 告诉你
that because there's no counterpart in
因为有一个 在 没有 对应
normal C code of how you'd even think
你会如何甚至认为普通的C代码
about it and it's fairly a little bit
关于它和它的相当一点点
harder to do cipher and you're going to
更难做密码和你要
have to do it in the bomb lab so here's
要做到这一点的炸弹实验室所以这里的
an example of a switch statement that is
即switch语句的一个例子
of nothing about this is useful except
的一无所知， 除了有用
to demonstrate some principles of how to
证明对如何一些原则
turn a switch statement into a assembly
把一个switch语句成装配
code so the point of it is as you know
代码，所以它的观点是，你 知道
and C you switch on a particular value
和C，你打开 一个特定的值
some type of integer value and then it
一些类型的整数值，然后将其
will match different cases where each of
将匹配不同的情况 下，每
these cases has to be some constant
这些案件必须有一些不变
numeric value constant integer value and
数值常数的整数值和
one of the weirdest features of C is if
的C的怪异的特征之一是，如果
you don't at the end of the case if you
你不要在你的情况下结束
don't explicitly say break it will do
没有 明确说破它会做
what's known as falling through so in
什么作为通过这样的下跌
this example here it will divide Y by Z
这个例子在这里它将除以zÿ
and then it will just glide right into
然后它只会滑翔 右转入
this statement that adds e to W this is
这种说法，增加了Ë至W，这是
by the way like one of the worst design
通过像最差设计的一个方式
decisions in the history of programming
在节目的历史决定
languages
语言
and it's been the cause of more and more
它已经越来越多的原因
you know art break and bugs that nobody
你知道艺术突破和错误 ，没有人
could understand than any other single
能理解比其他任何一个
part of the language and for some
语言和某些部分
bizarre reason they've kept it alive
奇怪的原因 ，他们已经把它活着
even into Java and all these other
即使进入Java和所有这些其他
languages that fix a lot of the worst
该解决很多 最坏的语言
parts you know the most dangerous parts
部分你知道最危险的部分
of C but somehow they kept this suture
的 C，但不知何故，他们一直在 这个 缝合
and so just as a advice as a programmer
所以只是作为一个建议，作为一个程序员
if you ever ever use this where you
如果你永远永远使用这个，你
purposely want it to go from one case to
有意想让它去从一个案例
another you should have to put a comment
另一个你应该把评论
in there to say trust me I really did
在那里说相信我， 我真的 做到了
want it to fall through I know you
希望落空我知道你
almost never want to do this but I do
几乎从来没有想这样做， 但我
here so that's a fairly common
这里所以这是一个相当 普遍
convention I don't know how many times
会议上， 我不知道有多少次
I've had bugs that were because I forgot
我已经说了，因为我忘了虫子
to put brakes in anyways enough of my
把 制动器反正够我
editorializing the other feature you see
编者按你看到的其他功能
and see is you can insert a bunch up
而看到的是，你可以插入一个聚成一团
multiple cases if you think of it that's
多情况下，如果你认为它这是
just a special case of the fall through
只是 秋天的 一个特例 通过
right the case five has nothing to do
右侧为 五个无关
but to fall through to six but so that's
但通过下降到六，但所以这是
the same general way and there's nothing
大致相同的办法并没有什么
that's not that's not bad and it doesn't
这不是，这不是坏的，它不
require a comment and the other one is
需要注释，另外一个是
that there's a default so if none of
，有一个默认的，所以如果没有的
these cases match either because X was 0
这些案件匹配要么是因为X为 0
or smaller or X was a really big number
或更小或X是一个非常大的数字
or in this case if X were 4 there's no
或在这种情况下，如果X是 4没有
matching case and of course you also
匹配的情况下，当然你也
know that these cases don't have to be
知道这些 情况不必是
in any particular order is it so that's
在任何特定的顺序是它所以这是
all the sort of features of a case
所有的排序的情况下的特性
statement of a switch statement turn up
switch语句的语句转起来
so normally if you write this in sort of
所以一般来说，如果你在那种写
if you were told
如果你被告知
thou shalt not use switch statements
你不可使用 switch语句
anymore what you'd probably do is write
再有什么你可能做的是写
this big long chain of if else if else
如果其他的if else的这个大长链
is else right and you'd expect that to
是别人的权利， 你会期望， 要
be the machine code but it's not and so
是 机器代码，但它不是 等
let me show you what the machine code
让我告诉 你什么是机器代码
does
不
it's kind of a long story so think of
它是一种长的故事 这么认为的
the general form of it as being some
它的一般形式为一些
blocks of code the entry points of which
的代码块，其中的入口点
are labeled by these case values and
由这些情况下值标记和
then the blocks
那么块
you know string together in various
你在不同的共同认识串
different ways and do various things
不同的方式和做各种事情
what I'm going to do is compile a code
我什么都做 的是编译代码
for all of those blocks and store them
所有这些块，并将其储存
away in some part of memory load up
远在存储器某些部分加载
memory to contain these code blocks and
存储器来包含这些代码块和
then I'm going to build a table and each
那么我要建立一个表 ，每个
entry of this table describes the
此表 的条目描述了
starting location of one of these code
开始的这些码的一个的位置
blocks and I'll put them in order of my
块，我把他们 的 订单 我
case labels if I have you know I want to
标签的情况下，如果我有你知道 我要
span a scope from well it's assumed zero
涵盖从那么它的假设零范围
but typically that's not the case
但通常认为并非如此
zero up to n minus one
零到N减一个
I'll have this table will have that many
我也会有这样的表将有很多
entries of addresses to tell me where
地址条目告诉我在哪里
these code blocks are located and then
这些代码块位于和然后
I'm going to use this really cool
我要 利用这个很酷
instruction which is a sort of like it's
指令这是一个有点像它的
as if you it's like a ray indexing so if
因为如果你把它像一个光线索引，所以如果
you think of a ray indexing it means you
你觉得射线索引就意味着你
can grab a value out of the middle of
能抢到值超出中间
some you know array some set of values
一些你知道数组的一些设定值
without having to step through them one
而不必通过它们的步骤 一个
by one and it's the same idea here that
由之一，它 在这里 是同样的想法 ，
I will take my value and use that to
我将我的价值，并用它来
figure out directly where I should jump
找出直接在这里我要跳
to a block of code without having to
到的代码 ， 而无需一个块
step through a bunch of other conditions
通过一堆其他条件步骤
so and you can see the efficiency again
所以，你可以再次看到效率
from that it's the difference between
从它的 之间 的 区别
sort of in one step knowing exactly
那种一步 到位知道 到底
where you want to be versus stepping
要成为与步进
through you know on average n over two
通过你知道n平均超过两
conditions to get to where I want to go
条件去的地步，我想去
so let's look at this at the assembly
让我们看看这个在装配
code level and it's a little bit of a
代码级，它是一个一点点
long thing because we have to build some
长长的东西，因为我们必须建立一些
machinery around this so here's my
所以在这里解决这个机器是我的
example I've got three arguments
例如我有三个参数
so just remember I told you our VI and
所以只记得我告诉你，我们的 VI和
our si for the first two arguments the
我们对前两个参数 的 SI
third argument is in RDX and here's the
第三个参数是RDX和这里的
beginning of the switch code it's just
开始拨码开关的，它只是
making a copy of argument Z here for
使得参数Z的副本，这里
some reason and then it's looking at
由于某种原因， 然后 在看
comparing X 2 6 and Y is 6 an important
比较X 2 6和Y 6 是 一个重要的
number because you see 6 was the largest
数，因为 你 看到 6为最大
value of any of my cases
的 我 的任何 情况下， 值
and now it's using a jump instruction to
现在它的使用跳转指令
go to LA what we'll find is that tells
去LA我们会发现， 告诉
you what the default behavior should be
你默认的 行为应该是什么
so it's sort of flushing away the the
所以这有点冲掉了的
default cases the cases that are either
默认情况下 是两种 情况
X is too small or X is too large and I
X是太小或 X是太大，我
should mention there's a clever trick
应该提到有一个巧招
there if you look at J a means jump
那里，如果你看看J A指跳
above that's the unsigned comparison and
上面这是无符号的比较
what it's making use of is our our
什么它利用的是我们的我们
result that you remember that if a
结果是，你要记住，如果一个
number is negative if you think of it as
数字为 负数，如果你认为它是
an unsigned value it becomes very large
一个无符号的价值就变得非常大
positive value so by doing the J a
正值 ，从而通过执行 J A
instead of AJ G I jump greater than I'm
而不是AJ GI的跳大于我
doing jump above it's saying I want to
做跳跃上面在说我要
jump to the default if either X is
跳转到 默认如果x是
greater than 6 but also it will cause it
大于6也将导致 其
to jump if X is less than 0 got it so
跳如果X 小于 0拿到这么
it's a clever trick of unsigned versus
它是一个无符号的巧招 对
signed numbers is taking advantage of
有符号数是趁着
and then the final part is this is the
然后将最后一部分是这样的
real heart of the work this is my very
工作的真正心脏，这是 我很
special go-to instruction that lets me
特别去到指令，让我
index into a table and extract out of
索引到表，并提取出 的
that an address and then jump to that
该地址，然后跳转到该
address so that's what lets me go
地址，这就是让我去
directly to some block of code based on
直接将一些代码块基于
whether my values we'll see will be in
我们是否我的价值观会看到将 在
the range between 0 and 6 so there'll be
0和6之间的范围，从而就会有
seven entries in that table
七个条目在 该表
one one thing just to keep track up for
一个一件事，只是为了 保持跟踪 弥补
later you'll see that for some reason
以后你会看到 ，由于某些原因
the GCC said you know if I look at all
海湾合作委员会说，你知道，如果我看所有
the code I actually don't use W as
代码其实我不使用W作为
initialized very much so I won't bother
初始化非常多，所以我不会打扰
doing it until somewhere within the code
这样做，直到某个地方的代码中
blocks so just we'll have to keep track
块，这样只是 我们必须 跟踪
of that here okay so this is the magic
的是，这里 好了 ，所以这是一个神奇的
instruction and now if we look and this
指令 现在如果我们 看看这个
is all assembly code you'll see this is
在所有的汇编代码，你会看到这是
the actual jump table and it's
实际跳转 表和它的
constructed it specified in assembly
它构建的在组件中指定
code it's the job of the assembler to
代码是汇编 到工作
actually fill in the contents of this
实际上填补了这样的内容
table excuse me but what the assembly
表原谅我，但是什么大会
code is telling the assembler is I need
代码 是告诉汇编器是 我需要的
a quad it's just a declaration to say I
四，它只是一个声明，说我
need an 8 byte value here and that value
在这里需要一个8字节的值和值
should match whatever address you decide
应与你决定什么地址
you later determine is the address of
您后来决定是地址
where I'm going to stick a label 8 and
我要去哪里贴标签和8
all these other ones and these are in
所有这些其他的， 这些都是在
the order as I mentioned from x equals 0
正如我从X所提及的顺序等于0
through 6 and we can already see a few
到6，我们已经可以看到几个
cases that are interesting here let me
是有趣的情况在这里让我
see if I've got a picture on this
看看，如果我已经有了 这一张图片
yeah
是啊
so we can actually already see some of
所以我们实际上可以看到已经有些
the logic of this switch statement built
这个switch语句 的 内置逻辑
into the ordering of entries in this
进入条目在此排序
table so in particular there is no case
表，以便特别是没有的情况下
zero here so case zero should be the
零这里，所以零的情况下应该是
default there is no case for here the
默认情况下有是这里的任何情况下
case for should be the default and it
案例应该是默认的 ，它
turns out and we already saw before the
事实证明，我们之前已经看到
J a instruction going to LA so L eight
J A指令去 LA如此 大号8
is actually where the code block is
实际上是在码块是
going to be for the default case so you
将成为默认的情况下，所以你
see basically you can think of this as
看基本上 就可以 认为这 是
sometimes kept having holes in your
有时保持具有孔的
switch statement and we're going to just
switch语句和我们要公正
fill in those holes by saying those
说那些填补这些漏洞
should go to the default case and here
应到默认 情况下，在这里
you'll notice that they're not put in
你会发现 ，他们 没有放
any particularly logical order a one
任何特别逻辑顺序一个一个
thing you'll see again is L 7 is
您将再次看到的是L7的
repeated twice here because it covers
这里重复两次，因为它涵盖了
both cases five and six so again you'll
两种情况下， 五 ，六，以便再次你会
see that sort of doubling up is handled
看到那种增加了一倍的处理
automatically by the jump table we'll
自动跳转表 ，我们将
give you the same address for multiple
给你同样的地址多
different cases
不同的情况下，
okay and now the rest of it is to look
还好 ，现在 它的 其余部分 是看
at the various code blocks and this by
在各码块并且这由
the way I'm showing you I took a file
我展示你的方式，我花了一个文件
and I'm you know extracted little bits
而且我知道你有点提取位
of it but normally you're looking at
它但是 通常你在看
this whole listing in one big order so
在一个大的订单，这个整体上市等等
now we can look at the individual code
现在我们可以 看个人代码
blocks and see what's going on and
块，看看发生了什么事情，并
you'll see for example case one told me
你会看到例如情况下，一个告诉我
to multiply two numbers and you'll see
到两个数相乘，你会看到
that the break in the general it's just
在 一般的突破，它只是
going to be turned into return
要 变成 回报
instructions here because my function go
在这里说明，因为我的功能去
sorry to jump in code you see this
遗憾的代码跳你看这
function did a switch statement and then
功能做了一个switch语句，然后
whatever whatever gets computed within
无论什么被中计算
the switch statement gets returned as a
switch语句获取返回的
result of this so the compiler doesn't
这个结果让编译器不
actually come to a single point and say
其实到了一个单点，并说
okay everyone returned at this point it
还好大家都回来在这一点上
just sticks returns directly in wherever
只是坚持直接回报的地方
these breaks occur
这些断裂发生
so here it does a multiply and a return
所以这里做了乘法和返回
here is actually a curious by the way
这里实际上是一个奇怪的方式
I'm always somewhat surprised by what
总是让我感到什么有点吃惊
the compiler does it is never exactly
编译器确实这是从来没有完全相同
what you'd expect so in particular it it
你期望什么，所以特别是它
patched together this fall through case
拼凑今秋通过案例
by two blocks of code and it had to do
通过两个代码块，它不得不做
these separately because remember W was
这些分别，因为记得 Mw为
not set before I entered the these code
没有设置之前，我进入了这些代码
blocks it deferred setting that and here
块并推迟设置，并在这里
I hit k3 and all of a sudden I actually
我打 了一个突然 我 的 K3 和 实际上 都
need whatever W was which was one and so
需要什么W¯¯ 是这是一个等
I guess the complier said well gosh I
我猜编译说好天哪我
guess I better set W to one here before
想我最好把W到一个之前在这里
we continue so as a result it sort of
我们继续这样的 结果，它像是
creates two code blocks but it jumps
创建两个代码块，但它跳跃
from the second one this block into
从第二个 该块成
partway through this other block here's
在这里中途通过这个其他块的
some actual yeah so here's the actual
一些实际的耶所以这里的实际
code this is the block that does the
代码这 是确实的 块
division it's very quickly how you have
分工是非常快，你怎么有
to write division discovered in the book
写师在书中发现
I won't go through it here and then this
我不会通过它放在这里，然后这个
jump l6 is what I say go to merge and
跳L6是什么，我说去 合并，
the merge is where you're bringing these
合并是你们把这些
two cases together here is where it's
2案件聚集在这里是它的
setting L to one again it's making use
设置L到一个重新它利用
of this feature and that the upper 32
该特征的， 并且上部32
bits get set to zeros so I I can use a
位都设置为零 ， 这样II可以使用
move L instruction here yes question
搬到这里提单资料是问题
did not have the code for what no the
没有什么无码
jump table is sort of embedded let me
跳转表之类的嵌入式让我
just show you real quick
只是告诉你真正的快
no probably bad idea the jump if you
没有可能坏主意跳，如果你
look at the the dot s file the assembly
看的点S文件汇编
code file Oh
代码文件哦
all this stuff I'm showing you I've
所有这些东西我展示你我
extracted out of that but it's all in
提炼出来 的那个，但是这一切都在
there
那里
and so that the compiler generated these
并且使得编译器生成的这些
tables at least the sort of framework
表至少那种框架
for these tables the details of which
这些表 的细节的
gets filled in by the assembler so it is
得到由汇编填满，所以它是
generated by the compiler
由编译器生成
okay so that just shows you this one
好吧，这只是 说明你这一个
example of handling a particular way to
示例的处理 一特定的方式
handle the fall through case and then
办理落空的情况下，然后
the remaining ones again you'll see here
其余的再你会看到这里
I got if I get to this case I need the
我如果我得到这个情况下，我需要的
fact that W is initialized to 1 so we'll
事实上W被初始化为1，所以我们会
do so here in the default case it just
这样做这里的默认情况下，它只是
designs to 2w and so that's all it does
设计2W的，因此这就是它所做的一切
so anyways I've actually shown you all
所以反正我实际上显示你所有
the code blocks but I've shown you one
代码块，但 我向您展示一个
by one but they're just all kind of
通过一个，但他们 只是都挺
strong in the file and in no particular
强的文件，并 没有特定的
order it doesn't matter what orders they
为了它什么并不重要 ，他们的订单
are yes yep so that was the reason for
是是是的，这样 是为原因
that jump above at the beginning so this
上面跳开头所以这
jump above la was the way that if X was
跳上面拉的样子，如果X是
either less than 0 or greater than 6 it
或者小于 0或 大于6它
would go to the default case and it will
会去默认情况下，它会
only do this indexing trick if the if X
如果如果X只能这样做索引伎俩
is between 0 and 6 and that's typically
为0和6 之间 ， 这就是通常
the way this works that you'll see that
这个工作的方式，你会看到，
whatever range of values you give it has
无论值的范围 ，你给它具有
to figure out the smallest and the
找出最小，
largest one set up so it goes to the
最大的一个设置，以便它去
default case if it's out of that range
默认情况下，如果它指出范围
and then set up a table for the values
然后设置 一个表中的值
within that range question like some
像一些该范围内的问题
negative number - yeah does it try to do
负数-是它尝试做
the index into it with that X power so
该索引将其与 X功率 ，从而
the question I'm realize I should be
我的问题，认识到我应该是
repeating questions the question is what
重复提问的问题是什么
if it's a negative number for your case
如果这是你的情况下 ， 负数
which is perfectly legal it will
这是完全合法的它会
typically add a bias to it effectively
通常有效 增加偏向 于它
so that whatever your lowest value was
所以，无论 你的最低值
become 0 or it'll do something like that
成为0或者它会做这样的事情
to avoid having to do negative indexing
要避免做阴性对照索引
another question is he yes yeah so you
另一个问题是，他肯定是啊，所以你
can go from zero to a million yeah they
可以从零 到一百万啊，他们
could be you could go zero in a million
可能是你可以在一百万零走
and nothing in between right so you'd
并没有什么右之间，所以你会
have two cases you really don't want a
有两种情况下，你真的 不想要一个
million entry table for just two cases
对于只是其中两个 例子百万条目表
so it will turn it into a felt code but
所以它会变成 一个 毡代码，但
the clever thing that we'll do if you
聪明的事情， 我们会如果 你 这样做
know binary search
知道二进制搜索
they relies on the fact that it knows in
他们依赖于它知道 的事实
advance all the values and it will
推进 所有的值，它 会
actually set up a tree of it Phelps's so
实际上建立的是 菲尔普斯的这么 一棵树
really it will do it if you want to
真的会做，如果你想
thank algorithmically it does it with a
感谢算法是用做它
logarithmic number of tests rather than
测试对数数量，而不是
a linear number of test question
的测试问题的线性数
oh yeah
哦耶
yeah so so there's two inches that one
是啊所以所以有2英寸一个
is this which I actually answered both
这是我居然回答都
now if one is what if there's some
现在，如果一个是什么，如果有一些
negative values or what if the lowest
负值或者什么，如果最低
number is 5700 right well what it will
数字是5700右以及怎样对
typically do is put some bias and you'll
通常做的就是把一些偏见， 你会
add or subtract some value so that the
加上或减去某个值，以 使
first case is at value 0 so that's where
第一种情况是在值 0，这就是
it handles you know ones that are just
它处理你知道 那些只是
completely out of range and the other is
完全超出 范围 ，而另一个是
what if it's a really big spread of
如果它是一个非常大的传播
values and relatively sparse how much
值和相对稀疏多少
you're using it and there it will revert
你使用它，有 它会恢复
to FL code and the compiler has its own
到FL代码和编译器具有自己
rules about how it does these things you
它是如何做这些事规则， 你
can sort of run experiments and try and
可以排序的运行试验和尝试，
reverse engineer because you know these
逆向工程，因为你知道这些
are all valid questions by the way
是 由道路上的 一切有效 的问题
appreciative
欣赏的
okay so we're going to get through this
好了，所以我们要通过这个来获得
Oh
哦
so anyways and like I said I think in my
所以反正就像我说的，我认为在我的
own experience you know understanding
自己的经验 ，你知道的理解
the conditionals you can kind of figure
在条件语句可以种人物
that out it's intuitive sort of feels
说出来 它的直观 感觉 排序 的
like what you'd expect a program to do
就像你所期望的程序做什么
whereas a switch statement is maybe
而switch语句 也许是
unexpected it's a way to do something
意想不到的是一种方式做一些事情
that is not totally obvious but then
这不是完全 明显，但随后
when you think about it and appreciate
当你想想看，欣赏
it it's actually it gives you a good
它它实际上它给你一个很好的
performance boost you know again
你再知道性能提升
algorithmically this jump table makes it
该算法跳转表使它
so it's a constant time a constant
所以这是一个固定的时间常数
number of steps to get to where you need
步数来得到 你需要的地方
to in the switch statement if you just
在switch语句 如果你只是
get it linearly one after the other then
得到它的线性一个接一个，然后
that would be linear time and you'd
这将是 线性的 时间，你会
expect on you know if everything's
希望你知道，如果一切都
uniform and average about how you'd be
均匀， 平均约 你 怎么 会
about halfway through on average if
大约一半的平均，如果
you're if it's sparse you'll see it will
你如果是稀疏，你会看到它会
set up a tree of conditionals so it can
设立条件句的树，以便它可以
do in logarithmic time so no matter what
做对数 时间，所以无论什么
it will be better than just what you get
它会比你得到的只是什么更好
in the obvious form of your felts I saw
在毛毯的明显形式只见
a question over here
在这里的一个问题
well the good news is I don't set up the
那么好消息 是，我不 成立
jump tree the compiler sets up to jump
跳树编译器设置到跳
tree right but if you're asking if I
树的权利，但如果你问我是否
were a compiler how would I set up the
是一个编译器我将如何建立
jump tree right which is a good question
跳树权这是一个很好的 问题
if you know binary search right that
如果你知道二进制搜索正确的
you've got a range of values and you
你已经有了一个范围值，你 的
pick you compare it to the middle value
接你比较它 的中间值
and it's either less or it's greater or
它要么少，或者它大于或
equal and if it's less than you sort of
平等的，如果它比你少的排序
recursively handle the one set and if
递归处理一组，如果
it's greater the other hat that's
这是更大的其他帽子 那
exactly what these trees look like so
正是这些树看起来像这样
they're balanced binary trees and
他们是平衡二叉树和
they're taking advantage of the fact
他们正在采取的事实的优点：
that in --see which is not true in all
在--see这是不正确的 所有
languages that all the the case
语言，所有的情况下，
conditions you're looking at our
你看我们的条件
constants they're determined when the
他们确定的常数时，
compiler is doing the compilation those
编译器做这些编译
are constant values so it can can sort
是恒定值，以确保可以进行排序
them figure out how many there are what
他们找出 有多少是什么
range of values so there are decide
值的范围，从而有决定
which version to do this and generate
哪个版本要 做到这一点，并生成
the code other questions so these are
代码的其他问题等等这些都是
all good and it's a very good question
所有的好， 这是一个非常好的问题
so and you're starting to think about
所以，您 开始 思考
you know which is the way that computer
你知道 它是 计算机 的方式
scientist should think is how do you
科学家 应该思考的是如何做的你
take some idea I've seen one case of
采取一些想法，我见过的一个案例
well how do I handle condition X and
以及如何处理条件X1和
condition Y and you know what happens if
条件Y，你知道会发生什么
this that's exactly what we do we sort
这一点，也 正是我们做什么，我们的排序
of we're never happy with a simple
我们是 用一个简单的 从来都是不快乐
explanation we want to understand how we
解释我们要了解我们
could actually implement it as a program
实际上可以实现它作为一个程序
if we ever had to do so
如果我们不得不这么做
so and so just in general that the main
某某只是一般 主
thing you see is that there's a fairly
你看到的是， 有一个相当
limited in bag of tricks for which the
有限 的锦囊 为其
program implements conditional
程序执行条件
constructs you've seen basically three
构建你见过三个基本
one is to use conditional jumps go to
一种是使用条件跳转到
different parts of the code another to
代码另一个 的 不同 部分
use conditional moods and the third is
使用条件的情绪 ;三是
to use this jump table idea and those
使用这个跳转表的想法和那些
are really that puts a little bit to do
真的是把一点点 做
of procedures consider all there is and
程序考虑 所有有和
all the other stuff you see in a program
你在程序中看到其他的东西
that sort of changes the flow of
那种改变流动
execution or what gets executed are all
什么得到执行的执行或全部
built out of those basic primitives and
内置了这些基本图元和
that's generally true that what we see
这是一般不错 ，我们所看到的
is when you go from C codes of machine
就是当你从机器的C ^码去
code you often have to kind of piece
代码， 你 经常要一种部件
together various low-level instructions
一起各种低级别的指令
to implement some higher-level construct
实现一些更高级别的结构
and so we've seen these all in different
所以我们在不同的都看到了这些
form stone and next time then we'll talk
形成结石和下一次再说吧
about procedures and that as you can
有关程序和，你可以
imagine a fairly major topic because it
想象一下，因为 它 相当大话题
is worth one entire procedure okay very
值得一个整个程序非常 好
good thank you
好 谢谢